Jerome Samuels

07794800128 jeromesamuels95@gmail.com

Personal Summary

I'm an enthusiastic alumni of the AWS Re/Start programme, where I learned the fundamentals of Linux, Python and AWS, amongst other technical and behavioural skills. I also have experience working as a 2nd Line Technician, where I learned to work to deadlines and communicate effectively with customers and stakeholders.

Technical Skills & Qualifications

- Linux
- Python
- Bash Scripting
- Networking
- Information Security
- Databases (MySQL, DynamoDB)
- Working towards the Certified Cloud Practitioner qualification from AWS
- Proficient with Microsoft Excel (VLOOKUP, pivot tables, etc)
- AWS (CloudFormation, Lambda, Route 53, etc.)

Professional Experience

Generation - AWS Re/Start

August 2020 - Present

- Learned the fundamentals of the Linux OS, working with files and directories and also learning to automate tasks with Bash scripting and the crontab
- Utilised Python as a scripting language as well as using dictionaries, loops and functions to create calculators and other applications
- Consistently scored above 70% in our progress tests
- Collaborated effectively with my colleagues in all group tasks, often taking on a leadership role
- Studied concepts such as agile methodology along with the CI/CD pipeline so that I'd understand the DevOps landscape
- Gained a solid understanding of the fundamentals of cloud computing and studied various AWS services like EC2 and learned how they've revolutionised the way businesses use technology

Deliveroo - 2nd Line IT Support Technician

September 2018 - January 2020

- Provided technical support to our 20,000+ partnered restaurants via telephone and live chat services, in accordance with the agreed SLAs, resolving over 85% of these issues on the call
- Kept my technical knowledge up to date through continuous research, allowing me to more effectively answer inquiries and outline solutions for customers facing issues with our Android tablets
- Organised and hosted training sessions for incoming support technicians where I explained our software and protocols clearly and efficiently
- Displayed strong communication and interpersonal skills while dealing with customers, no matter how difficult the situation
- Collaborated with QA team to resolve technical incidents affecting tablets across multiple sites
- Utilised Soti Mobicontrol (an enterprise mobility management software) to configure new tablets for restaurants, and also provide technical support by controlling their devices remotely

Education

University of Nottingham - BSc Neuroscience (2.1)

September 2014 - July 2018

• Through my course, I became proficient with Microsoft excel for the purposes of analysing and interpreting data

Loreto College

2012 - 2014

A-Levels in Chemistry, Biology and Psychology

Stretford Grammar School

2007 - 2012

11 GCSEs including A's and B's in English and Maths respectively

External Links

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeromesamuels5